In the end, he sees everything.
The Final Cut is a drama, mystery, science fiction film directed by Omar Naim.
Set in a world with memory implants, Alan Hakman is a 'cutter'—someone with the power of final edit
over people's recorded histories—but his latest assignment puts him in great danger.
Alan W. Hakman, played by Robin Williams.
Delila, played by Mira Sorvino.
Fletcher, played by Jim Caviezel.
Thelma, played by Mimi Kuzyk.
Jennifer Bannister, played by Stephanie Romanov.
Isabel Bannister, played by Genevieve Buechner.
The Final Cut is a 2004 science fiction psychological
thriller film written and directed by Omar Naim.
It stars Robin Williams, Jim Caviezel, Mira Sorvino, Mimi Kuzyk,
Stephanie Romanov, Genevieve Buechner and Brendan Fletcher.
The film takes place in a setting where brain implants make it
possible to record the sight and sound of entire lives.
Williams plays a professional who specializes in editing the memories of
unsavory people into uncritical memorials that are played at funerals.
The film won the award for best screenplay at the Deauville American Film Festival and was nominated
for best film at the Sitges Film Festival and Berlin International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of dying and death, boss, microchip, secret.
The tone is intense and emotional and thought_provoking.